Finding Aid for the John Waldie Papers, 1793-1862
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
John Waldie Papers,
1793-1862
169
Waldie, John, 1781-1862
7 cartons (7 linear ft.)
University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Department of Special Collections. Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
John Waldie (1781-1862) was the administrator of Hendersyde Park at Kelso, Roxburghshire, Scotland. The collection consists of 7 volumes of letters to John Waldie (1793-1841), 74 journal volumes, 11 volumes on travels transcribed from the journals, and 1 volume of passports (1827-1837).
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Advance notice required for access.
Additional Physical Form Available
A copy of the original version of this online finding aid is available at the UCLA Department of Special Collections for in-house consultation and may be obtained for a fee. Please contact:
Public Services Division
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library
Box 951575
Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575
Telephone: 310/825-4988 (10:00 a.m. - 4:45 p.m., Pacific Time)
Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Robert D. Steedman, purchase, 1957.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 4233947
Biography
Waldie was born in 1781; attended University of Edinburgh; awarded D.Lit; assumed the administration of Hendersyde Park at Kelso, Roxburghshire, Scotland, shortly before the death of his father, George Waldie, in 1826; traveled extensively in Europe; he died in 1862.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of 7 volumes of letters to John Waldie (1793-1841), 74 journal volumes, 11 volumes on travels transcribed from the journals, and 1 volume of passports (1827-1837). Includes an eyewitness narrative of the Battle of Waterloo in 1815. Journals provide commentary on the music, art, and theater of the period in Britain and Europe.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Collection is arranged chronologically.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Waldie, John, 1781-1862--Archives.; Waldie, John, 1781-1862--Diaries.; Europe--Description and travel.; Europe--Social life and customs--19th century.
Container List
- Letters Addressed to John Waldie Esquire
  - August 28, 1793-March 11, 1808. (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - January 30, 1809-August 28, 1811. (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - March 20, 1824-November 21, 1828. (Box 1, Volume 3)
  - February 14, 1833-October 14, 1835. (Box 2, Volume 4)
  - February 1, 1836-August 3, 1837. (Box 2, Volume 5)
  - October 1, 1839-December 31, 1840. (Box 2, Volume 6)
  - January 3, 1841-December 31, 1841. (Box 2, Volume 7)
- Journals, 1799-1862
  - 1799-1800 & 1801., no.8 (Box 3, Volume 4)
    John Waldie. Newcastle.
  - April 23-August 31, 1802., no.9 (Box 3, Volume 5)
    Containing travels in Holland, Flanders, & France in 1802.
  - March 24-May 19, 1803., no.10 (Box 3, Volume 7)
  - May 20, 1803-August 8, 1803., no.11 (Box 3, Volume 8)
  - August 9, 1803-May 14, 1804., no.12 (Box 3, Volume 9)
  - May 14, 1804-March 12, 1805., no.13 (Box 3, Volume 10)
  - March 12, 1805-September 27, 1805., no.14 (Box 3, Volume 11)
  - September 28, 1805-May 31, 1806., no.15 (Box 3, Volume 12)
  - June 1-July 31, 1806., no.16 (Box 3, Volume 13)
    Includes Cornish Adventures.
  - April 5-August 10, 1807., no.17 (Box 3, Volume 15)
  - April 1-June 15, 1808., no.18 (Box 3, Volume 17)
    Travels.
  - February 1-July 3, 1809., no.19 (Box 3, Volume 19)
  - July 4-September 16, 1809., no.20 (Box 3, Volume 20)
  - April 5-August 31, 1813., no.21 (Box 3, Volume 28)
    Irish travels.
  - September 3, 1814-May 3, 1815., no.22 (Box 3, Volume 31)
  - May 4-July 31, 1815., no.23 (Box 3, Volume 32)
  - July 15-September 15, 1816., no.24 (Box 3, Volume 35)
    Travels in Falnders, Germany, Switzerland, Italy, France.
    Part 1 of Continental travels (July 15, 1816-August 31, 1817) in 6 vol.
  - September 16-December 8, 1816. Part 2., no.25 (Box 3, Volume 36)
  - December 9, 1816-February 16, 1817. Part 3., no.26 (Box 3, Volume 37)
  - February 17-May 2, 1817. Part 4., no.27 (Box 4, Volume 38)
  - July 1-August 31, 1817. Part 6 (Includes itinerary of travels)., no.28 (Box 4, Volume 40)
  - September 17, 1818-April 19, 1819., no.29 (Box 4, Volume 42)
    Journals of travels to France, Spain, Italy & Germany in 1818, 1819, 1820 (vol.1).
  - April 20-July 30, 1819., no.30 (Box 4, Volume 43)
    Travels in France, Spain, Italy & Germany, 1818-1820 (vol.2).
  - July 31-November 1819., no.31 (Box 4, Volume 44)
    Travels in France, Spain, Germany, 1818-1820 (vol.3).
  - December 1, 1819-May 23, 1820., no.32 (Box 4, Volume 45)
    Travels in France, Spain, Germany, 1818-1820 (vol.4).
  - May 24-July 9, 1820., no.33 (Box 4, Volume 46)
    Travels in France, Spain, Germany, 1818-1820 (vol.5).
  - July 10, 1820-March 24, 1821., no.34 (Box 4, Volume 47)
    London.
  - March 26, 1821-April 9, 1822., no.35 (Box 4, Volume 48)
  - April 10, 1822-August 31, 1823., no.36 (Box 4, Volume 49)
  - May 25-September 26, 1827., no.37 (Box 4, Volume 53)
    Travels, vol.1 begins July 14, p.49.
  - September 27-December 29, 1827., no.38 (Box 4, Volume 54)
    Travels, vol.2; Germany, Italy, Switzerland, France, 1827 & 1828.
  - December 30, 1827-June 11, 1828., no.39 (Box 4, Volume 55)
    Travels, vol.3; Germany, Styria, Carniola, Italy, Switzerland, France in 1827 & 1828.
  - June 12, 1828-July 28, 1829., no.40 (Box 4, Volume 56)
    Travels, vol.4.
  - July 29, 1829-June 9, 1830., no.41 (Box 4, Volume 57)
    Including five months residence in Paris.
  - June 10, 1830-September 5, 1831., no.42 (Box 4, Volume 58)
  - September 6, 1831-August 31, 1832., no.43 (Box 4, Volume 59)
  - September 1, 1832-January 10, 1833., no.44 (Box 4, Volume 60)
    Travels, vol.1 begins October 1832, p.69.
  - January 11-May 31, 1833., no.45 (Box 4, Volume 61)
    Travels, vol.2; France, Savoy, Italy, Sicily, Malta, Part of Switzerland.
  - June 1-September 30, 1833., no.46 (Box 4, Volume 62)
    Travels, vol.3.
  - October 1, 1833-February 28, 1834., no.47 (Box 4, Volume 63)
    Includes itinerary of vol.3.
  - March 1-June 20, 1834., no.48 (Box 4, Volume 64)
    Travels, vol.5.
  - June 21, 1834-July 15, 1835., no.49 (Box 5, Volume 65)
  - July 15, 1835-January 10, 1836., no.50 (Box 5, Volume 66)
    Travels, vol.1 begins August 13, after p.45.
  - January 11, 1836-June 18, 1836., no.51 (Box 5, Volume 67)
    Travels, vol.2; France, Switzerland, Savoy, Italy, Ionian islands, Greece, Asia Minor, Turkey, Hungary, Austria, etc.
  - June 18-October 31, 1836., no.52 (Box 5, Volume 68)
  - November 1, 1836-May 23, 1837., no.53 (Box 5, Volume 69)
    Travels, vol.4; begins with Vienna.
  - May 24, 1837-June 17, 1838., no.54 (Box 5, Volume 70)
    Travels, vol.5; begins Clermont, ends London.
  - June 18, 1838-July 8, 1839., no.55 (Box 5, Volume 71)
    London to Torquay.
  - July 9, 1839-December 6, 1839., no.56 (Box 5, Volume 72)
    Torquay to Hendersyde Park.
  - December 7, 1839-September 4, 1840., no.57 (Box 5, Volume 73)
    Hendersyde Park to Buxton.
  - September 15, 1840-July 31, 1841., no.58 (Box 5, Volume 74)
    Buxton to Hendersyde Park.
  - August 1, 1841-May 16, 1842., no.59 (Box 5, Volume 75)
    Hendersyde Park to London.
  - May 16, 1842-October 7, 1842., no.60 (Box 5, Volume 76)
    Travels, 6 weeks in Belgium, Rhenish Prussia & Nassau, 1842. vol. ends in London.
    London portion begins July 1842.
  - October 8, 1842-May 4, 1843., no.61 (Box 5, Volume 77)
    A winter in Paris, being nearly 7 months absence from Paris.
  - May 5, 1843-January 5, 1844., no.62 (Box 5, Volume 78)
    Barnes to Hendersyde Park.
  - January 6-October 21, 1844., no.63 (Box 5, Volume 79)
    Travels, vol.1 begins October 1, p.397. Journey to Lyons.
  - October 21, 1844-April 29, 1845., no.64 (Box 5, Volume 80)
    Travels, vol.2; Switzerland, Italy, winter in Rome.
  - April 29-September 1, 1845., no.65 (Box 5, Volume 81)
  - September 2, 1845-August 24, 1846., no.66 (Box 5, Volume 82)
    Hendersyde Park.
  - August 25, 1846-July 31, 1847., no.67 (Box 6, Volume 83)
    Hendersyde Park to York.
  - August 1, 1847-July 4, 1848., no.68 (Box 6, Volume 84)
    York to Malvern Wells.
  - July 4, 1848-June 12, 1849., no.69 (Box 6, Volume 85)
    Malvern Wells to London.
  - June 13, 1849-July 3, 1850., no.70 (Box 6, Volume 86)
    London to Hendersyde Park.
  - July 3, 1850-June 28, 1851., no.71 (Box 6, Volume 87)
    Newcastle to London.
  - June 29, 1851-September 21, 1852., no.72 (Box 6, Volume 88)
  - September 22, 1852-September 29, 1853., no.73 (Box 6, Volume 89)
    Hendersyde Park to Duddon Hall.
  - September 30, 1853-December 1, 1854., no.74 (Box 6, Volume 90)
    Duddon Hall to Hendersyde Park.
  - December 1, 1854-February 1, 1856., no.75 (Box 6, Volume 91)
    Hendersyde Park, 74 years, 9 months age-February 1, 1856. Has a 1600 volume library.
  - February 2-December 3, 1856., no.76 (Box 6, Volume 92)
    Hendersyde Park to Rome.
  - December 4, 1856-September 15, 1857., no.77 (Box 6, Volume 93)
    Rome to Hendersyde Park.
  - September 16, 1857-October 14, 1858., no.78 (Box 6, Volume 94)
  - October 15, 1858-October 19, 1859., no.79 (Box 6, Volume 95)
    Hendersyde Park to Penraig Anglesey.
  - May 22, 1862-., no.80 (Box 6, Volume 98)
    last entry, October 28.
  - Journal of a tour in Holland, Flanders, and France in the year 1802., no.81 (Box 6)
    Including itinerary.
  - Journal of travels in Flanders, Holland, and France in the year 1815., no.82 (Box 7)
  - Journals of travels in Flanders, Germany, Switzerland, Italy, and France in the years 1816 and 1817., no.83; (6 vol.) (Box 6)
    [vol.3 and 4, bound together]
  - Journal of travels in France, Spain, Italy, and Germany in the years 1818, 1819 and 1820., no.84; (5 vol.) (Box 7)
  - Above, vol.2., no.85 (Box 7)
  - Above, vol.3., no.86 (Box 7)
  - Above, vol.4., no.87 (Box 7)
  - Above, vol.5., no.88 (Box 7)
  - Travels in Germany, Styria, Carniola & Istria, Italy, Switzerland, and France in 1827 and 1828., no.89 (Box 7)
  - Above, vol.2, no title page., no.90 (Box 7)
  - Above, vol.3, no title page., no.91 (Box 7)
  - Above, vol.4., no.92 (Box 7)
  - Passports, 1827 to 1837., no.93 (Box 7)
  - Journal of a four month absence from England in the summer of 1815., no.94 (Box 7)
    Including a tour in Flanders, Holland, and France and a short residence at Brussels and Paris.
    [A manuscript transcription of Waterloo Days by Jane Waldie Watts]
Index of Correspondents
(This is an alphabetical list of correspondents in Volumes 1-7 (Boxes 1 and 2)
Achenhausen, Baroness d' née Acton vol.5: 34
Aglionby, Henry Aglionby (1790-1854) vol.2: 54, 57, 62-3, 94 vol.3: 38
Aldam, William vol.6: 47, 104, 106
Aldam, William Jr.? vol.6: 74, 118 vol.7: 63
Aretin, Baroness d vol.4: 84
D'Aroambal, Philippe vol.4: 24
Barrett, Edward vol.6: 16
Baruzzi, Giustiniano vol.3: 89
Bewicke, Calverley vol.6: 89 vol.7: 38, 80, 108
Bewicke, Mrs. Margaret vol.6: 123 vol.7: 124
Blackburn, Edward vol.1: 53-7, 63-4, 67
Blackburn, John, M.P. vol.1: 47-8, 74
J.W. letter to Blackburn vol.1: 51
Blackburn, John Sr. vol.1: 10
Blackett, Charles vol.1: 78, 90, 93, 98-9, 107 vol.2: 15, 22, 27, 30, 58-9, 83, 92 vol.3: 62 vol.6: 57
Braddyll, Colonel vol.7: 128
Brisbane, Sir Thomas (MacDougall) (1773-1860) vol.3: 67
Bucceuch, Duke of see also Scott (1806-1884) (?) vol.7: 112
Bulman, Arelia Elizabeth vol.3: 34 vol.5: 43, 62, 89 vol.6: 51; vol.7: 43, 71, 84
Bulman, Lt. Arch'd, R.N. vol.6: 41
Burdett, Miss vol.6: 98
Butler, Lady Eleanor (1745?-1829) vol.5: 85
Butler, Sir Thomas (1783-1861) vol.4: 118
Caldwell, Mrs. Ann vol.6: 6
Caldwell, Capt. Charles vol.7: 62
Cartwright, J. vol.5: 27
Case, Caroline vol.4: 53
Case, J. Ashton vol.4: 53
Catalani, Guglielmo vol.2: 36
Charlewood, Colonel vol.7: 130
Chatto, Elizabeth see also Potts, Elizabeth Chatto vol.1: 82, 89, 91
Chatto, John vol.1: 34, 85, 88 vol.3: 25, 36, 51, 53
Chiaveri, Luigi vol.4: 25 vol.5: 20
Christie, Langham vol.3: 9, 40, 49, 59, 81
Clark, Mrs. T. vol.1: 35-6, 83, 94, 96, 103, 112-13 vol.2: 4, 6
Clark, Prof. William (1788-1869) vol.2: 45
Collingwood, Mrs. Newnham vol.6: 126
Collins-wood, William G. vol.5: 31
Conway, William Augustus (1789-1828) vol.2: 8, 11, 14, 17, 56, 72
Cookburn, William vol.6: 83
Cookson, Elizabeth vol.3: 6, 11, 15, 28, 35, 55, 78, 80, 84, 92, 96 vol.4: 1, 8, 36, 40, 42, 49, 55, 61, 66, 84, 97, 107, 114 vol.5: 4, 22, 38, 63, 69, 82 vol.6: 7, 13, 34, 65, 72, 78, 91, 116, 137 vol.7: 15, 34, 76, 99, 103
Cookson, Isaac J. (1776-1851) vol.7: 64
Coventry, Nancy vol.4: 110
Cuthbert, Robert vol.5: 32, 49
Cuthbert, William vol.4: 15, 86, 89, 96, 104-05 vol.5: 3, 7, 14, 19 vol.6: 2
Cuthbert, William Jr. vol.4: 15, 60, 70, 75, 96, 98
Darwin, Dr. Erasmus (1731-1802) vol.1: 38
Davevae, T. vol.4: 23, 26
Denman, Benjamin William vol.3: 10, 48
Dickson, Mrs. Jane vol.7: 10, 18, 78, 95
Dickson, Sir William vol.6: 59
Donkin, Lady Anna Maria vol.6: 22, 139 vol.7: 123
Douglas, George vol.1: 68, 97 vol.2: 68-9, 71, 87
Drake, Lady vol.2: 24
Dunbar, Sir William R. vol.1: 84
Dundras, Miss vol.5: 45 vol.6: 90, 96
Dundras, Isabella vol.7: 45
Earle, Charles vol.4: 83, 87
Earle, W. [of Everton] vol.5: 23
Earle, William vol.3: 94 vol.4: 12, 47, 56, 72
Earle - see also Everton
Eaton, Charles Ormston vol.6: 141
Eaton, Charlotte Ann Waldie see also Waldie, Charlotte Ann vol.3: 74-5 vol.5: 40, 47, 52, 74, 81 vol.6: 3, 29, 38, 46, 54, 85, 112 vol.7: 1, 28, 105, 116, 124
Eaton, John R. (Dicky) vol.7: 121
Egremont, Sara vol.3: 58 vol.5: 91
Elliot, Elizabeth vol.3: 58 vol.5: 91
Elliot, Admiral George vol.4: 9 vol.5: 1
Elliot, John vol.6: 23 vol.7: 47
Elliot - see also under Minto
Ellison, N[athanial]? vol.2: 46, 60-1
Ende, Baron d'avon of Prussia vol.4: 26, 37
Everton, William Earle vol.5: 86
see also Earle, William of Everton
Farren, Mary vol.1: 101 vol.2: 74
Farren, Percival vol.1: 105
Forbes, Capt. James vol.3: 46, 52
Fraisenet, Mr. A. vol.4: 18
Grey, Earl vol.6: 61 vol.7: 69, 97
Griffith, Elizabeth Charlotte vol.5: 65 vol.6: 100?
Griffith, Richard vol.1: 81, 86, 92, 104 vol.2: 26, 73 vol.5: 71
Griffith, Trygarn vol.6: 28, 57, 64, 76, 92 vol.7: 15, 60, 102, 123
Hart, Miss S.C. vol.1: 102
Hassels, Mr. C.S. vol.5: 60
Hassells, Sophia vol.3: 95 vol.4: 6, 10, 19, 28, 41, 54, 94, 100, 121 vol.5: 28, 44, 55, 66, 79, 88 vol.6: 15, 37, 75, 101, 110, 125, 139 vol.7: 6, 52, 101, 127
Hawke, Mrs. vol.6: 45
Headley, Lady Ann vol.7: 32
Hervey, Colonel vol.4: 48
Hewitson, Henry vol.3: 39, 41, 56, 63, 71-3 vol.5: 68
Hinde, Mrs. H. vol.6: 32, 140
Hinde, Isabella H vol.7: 25
Hinde-Hodgson, John see also Hodgson, John vol.4: 109 vol.7: 31, 90, 100?
Hingant, Mr. vol.1: 16
Lamb, Warren vol.1: 9
Langhorne, Thomas vol.1: 12, 19, 20
Lauder, Sir Thomas Dick (1784-1848) vol.3: 61
Lewis, James (1786-1853) (?) vol.1: 31, 37
Lluellyn, R. vol.2: 20, 23, 25, 31, 33, 35, 37-9, 43, 49, 52, 55, 67, 70, 75-8, 81
Lowe, Mrs. vol.6: 102
Lundie, Jane vol.4: 71
Lundie, Rev. Robert vol.2: 29
MacDonald, Capt. G.G. RN vol.6: 109 vol.7: 12, 42, 51
Mathews, Mr. C. vol.3: 12, 19
Maude, Rev. John B. vol.3: 91
Maude, Mrs. R. vol.4: 80
Maude, T.M. vol.3: 37, 87 vol.4: 69 vol.5: 84
Maude, William vol.4: 57 vol.6: 14
Melgund, Lord vol.6: 49, 63
Mengden, Countess vol.6: 115
Minto - see also Elliott
Minto, Lady vol.4: 73; V: 87 vol.5: 87 vol.7: 25, 40, 56, 89, 98, 113
Minto, Lord vol.3: 24 vol.4: 13, 68, 108, 120 vol.6: 21, 63, 99 vol.7: 125
Minton, Earl of vol.5: 45
Monck, Sir Charles (1779-1867) vol.1: 115
Okell, Miss Elizabeth vol.6: 40 vol.7: 91
Ormonde, Lady vol.5: 30
Ormston, Barbara vol.1: 6, 13, 15, 27, 39, 72-3 vol.2: 12, 48, 82 vol.3: 21, 27 vol.4: 11, 44, 50, 76, 90, 93, 112 vol.5: 16, 24, 44, 53, 67 vol.6: 10, 27, 66, 71, 82, 93, 95, 108, 122, 132, 136 vol.7: 37, 41, 48, 55, 70, 79, 106, 114,
Ormston, M.A. vol.5: 75
Ormston MaryAnn(?) vol.1: 3, 7, 8 vol.6: 84
Ormston, Robert vol.5: 75 vol.6: 131
Palm, Baron (Württemberg) vol.4: 27
Pantaleo, Baron Francesco vol.5: 12, 15, 18, 25, 42, 59
Peltrani, Count Francesco vol.5: 64
Plunkett, Barnewell vol.1: 60
Poliganno, Duke de vol.4: 16
Politi, C vol.4: 20, 37
Polworth, Lady Harriet vol.5: 33 vol.6: 1, 44, 60, 77
Potts, Elizabeth Chatto see also Chatto, Elizabeth vol.4: 17, 34 vol.5: 6, 10, 13, 46 vol.3: 93
Potts, Thomas (1778-1842) vol.3: 18 vol.4: 34 vol.5: 78 vol.7: 59, 72, 81
Prendergart, Thomas vol.7: 128
Pringle, Alexander (1791-1857) vol.4: 59
Pringle, Lady Elizabeth vol.4: 119 vol.5: 93 vol.6: 39, 41 vol.7: 122
Pringle, Sir John (1784-1869) vol.2: 65 vol.3: 8 vol.4: 31, 52, 65, 119 vol.5: 17 vol.6: 35-6, 55, 140
Pringle, Robert vol.6: 117 vol.7: 44, 51
Pringle, William vol.3: 3, 29
Rawlinson, Catherine Waldie vol.1: 46
Rawlinson, John vol.4: 78, 102 vol.5: 73 vol.7: 74
Rawlinson, Mrs. vol.7: 120
Richardson, Mrs. C.E. vol.5: 35
Robertson, Mrs. M.J. vol.5: 50-1 vol.6: 52, 94 vol.7: 49, 82
Robson, James (1733-1806?) vol.2: 1
Robson, Dr. W. vol.3: 16 vol.5: 8, 56, 77 vol.7: 65, 126
Robyns, Miss Anne vol.1: 100, 106, 109, 116 vol.6: 28, 40, 44, 64, 88, 91, 93
Roxburghe, Harriet, Duchess of vol.5: 11, 37 vol.7: 86, 119, 129
Russell, Miss, Countess of Mulgrave vol.7: 24
Rutherford, Mrs. A.O. vol.4: 51 vol.6: 31, 48, 53, 73, 80, 97, 114, 121, 128, 134, 144 vol.7: 5, 54, 66, 72, 87
Rutherford, Mrs. M.A. vol.1: 95
Rutherford, Nancy vol.3: 33, 57, 82 vol.4: 38, 92
Rutherford, W.O. vol.7: 118
Rutherford, William Oliver (1798-1871) vol.3: 22
Saint Clair - see also Sinclair
Saint Clair, Charles vol.7: 46
Saint Clair, James vol.6: 24
Scott, Harriet, Lady Polworth vol.3: 14
Scott, Lord John vol.6: 19
Sererino, Prince Santa vol.4: 27
Sforza, Cardinal Riario vol.4: 2
Sinclair, Sir John vol.3: 30, 68, 76
Sinclair, Lady vol.3: 1, 79, 93 vol.4: 17, 22, 33, 35, 45, 58, 63, 77, 82, 111, 117 vol.5: 5, 21, 36, 48, 54, 70, 93 vol.6: 12, 39, 50, 81, 92, 98, 102, 111, 124, 134, 138 vol.7: 16, 21, 29, 32, 47, 53, 60, 85, 96, 107, 110
Sinclair, Lady Camilla vol.7: 115
Sinclair, Lord vol.4: 43 vol.5: 58, 72, 94 vol.6: 9, 23 vol.7: 43
Smail, Capt. J. vol.7: 35, 50
Smith, Lt. Bedford vol.2: 51, 53
Smith, Elizabeth Charlotte Griffith Bramston vol.6: 100 vol.7: 4, 8, 36, 58-9, 67, 73, 77, 85, 94, 103
Smith, Giacomo vol.5: 83, 95 vol.6: 20 vol.7: 22, 109
Smith, Robert vol.6: 51
Starke, Mrs. M. vol.4: 38 vol.5: 90
Stelling, Mrs. Hodgson vol.6: 138
Stevenson, Mr. vol.6: 42
Stewart, Mrs. Mary E. (?) vol.7: 129
Talbot de Malahide, Lady vol.7: 27, 30
Trevelyan, Julia vol.1: 108
Turner, Rev. William vol.7: 110
Vane, Sir Henry T. vol.1: 76
Vyvyan, Sir Vyell vol.2: 9
Waldie, Ann vol.1: 1, 2, 4, 11, 17, 22, 23, 26, 28-30, 32, 41, 50, 52, 62, 75, 117-8 vol.3: 54
Waldie, Charlotte Ann see also Eaton, Charlotte Ann Waldie (1788-1859) vol.1: 70, 79, 85, 87 vol.2: 5, 7, 13, 16, 21, 32, 34
Waldie, George vol.1: 22, 23, 26, 28-30, 41, 42, 44-5, 53, 62, 75, 117-8 vol.2: 19
Waldie, Jane Ormston see also Watts, Jane O. Waldie (1793-1826) vol.1: 5
Waldie, John vol.3: 86
Waldie, Maria Jane Griffith vol.1: 25, 33, 40, 43, 49, 117-8 vol.2: 18-19, 41, 90 vol.3: 65 vol.5: 9, 26, 41, 57, 61, 65 vol.6: 11 vol.7: 20, 33, 56, 58, 75, 88, 104
Waldie, William Jonathan vol.1: 71 vol.2: 3
Walker, Henry, vol.3: 85, 88
Walker, Mrs. Joe vol.7: 84
Walton, Lewis vol.1: 21
Watson, John Selby (?) (1804-1884) vol.3: 60, 66, 69
Watts, Capt. George Edward (1785-1860) vol.3: 50, 113
Watts, Jane Waldie see also Waldie, Jane O vol.3: 2, 4-5, 7, 13, 20, 26, 43-4
Watts, William vol.4: 106 vol.5: 2 vol.6: 103 vol.7: 39
Wichelo, Lt. M. dragooms vol.1: 24
Woodburn, William Paul vol.4: 39, 88 vol.7: 76, 83, 97
Wylde, Colonel vol.7: 46
Yates, Miss M. vol.2: 47, 79, 86, 89 vol.3: 70 vol.6: 21